smd.co.za 2016-04-01

# - Buy It. Fix It. Love It.

### Introduction

We respect the privacy of everyone who visits this website. As a result we would like to inform you regarding the way we would use your personal data. We recommend you to read this privacy policy so that you understand our approach towards the use of your personal data.

By submitting your personal data to us, you will be treated as having given your permission – where necessary and appropriate – for disclosures referred to in this policy.

  1. At times, SMD will collect certain personal information about customers and visitors to websites hosted by us. Such information will include both identifiable personal data, as well as non-identifiable personal. Identifiable personal information will be collected when you sign a contract for service with us, or use our website for a transaction or subscription service. Non-identifiable information is gathered automatically when you visit our website or those websites hosted by us, and stored for use in our system.
  2. The purpose of this privacy policy is to explain to customers what types of information we will collect and how that information is used. In most cases, we collect this information to ensure network integrity and that we continue to provide you with the most relevant content and best possible service that suits your needs. In some cases, we are required by law to collect personal information about customers. Except where the law requires otherwise, we undertake to protect the confidentiality of such data.

#### Confidentiality

  1. SMD respects customer privacy and the privacy of those accessing our website, or those websites hosted by us. We undertake to protect the confidentiality of our customers and users including all personal information supplied in the course of contracting with us for services. We undertake not to sell your personal information to third parties for commercial or marketing purposes.

#### Collection of Personal Data

  1. SMD collects personal data about our users when you visit a website hosted by us; register to be a buyer; respond to a customer questionnaire through the use of cookie technology. We may also combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from our business partners or affiliates. A cookie is a data file that sits on your computer hard disk. The cookie is placed there by a remote web server that you have visited using a browser like Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox or Internet Explorer. It is used to uniquely identify you during web interactions with a website and contains data parameters that allow the remote HTML server to keep a record of who you are, and what actions you take at the remote web site. You have the option to disable the cookie function in your browser, but will be restricted from accessing many sites as a result.

#### Use of Personal Data

  1. SMD may on occasion use your personal information to contact you about promotional offers; advise you of matters relevant to service provision and in some cases, solicit your feedback. However, SMD will provide you with an option within every communication to opt out of receiving any communications of this nature or you can contact our customer services representatives to ensure that you do not receive such promotional information, at +27-87-285-0232.
  2. SMD collects and shares aggregated user data with business partners, sponsors or other third parties for the purposes of developing content and ensuring relevant advertising and content, such user data will never be used to identify individual users. These business partners and affiliated companies do not have any independent right to share this information.
  3. SMD may log the websites you visit; collect IP addresses and information about your operating system and the type of browser you use for the purposes of network/system administration; to report aggregate information to our advertisers, and to audit the use of our site. This data however will not be used to identify individual users who will at all times remain anonymous.
  4. Any information SMD collects from you through correspondence with us, whether via e-mail, telephonically or by written letter, will only be used to address the matters within that correspondence. If this requires referring such correspondence within Company or to a third party to ensure customer service, your personal information will only be disclosed to the point necessary to address your query or concerns, and will otherwise be kept confidential.

#### Public Space (Bulletin Boards, Chat Rooms and Third-Party Sites)

  1. Any information that customers disclose in a public space, including on any bulletin board, chat room or any site Company may host for you, is available to anyone else who visits that space. SMD cannot safeguard any information you disclose there.

#### Site Linking

  1. SMD’s websites contain many links to sites that belong to third parties unrelated to us. SMD cannot be held responsible for any use of your personal information arising from you disclosing personal such information on third party sites. SMD cannot protect any information you may disclose on these sites and recommends that you review the privacy policy statements of those sites you visit.

#### Minors

  1. SMD will not enter into a service subscription contract with a minor unless such minor has explicit written consent from a parent or guardian to do so. Company undertakes not to contact minors about promotional offers or for marketing purposes without a parental consent.

#### Reservation of Rights

  1. SMD reserves the right to disclose information about customers where required in good faith, to do so by law or to exercise our legal rights or defend ourselves against legal claims.
  2. SMD further reserves the right to share information with law enforcement to investigate or prevent illegal activities being committed over our network.
  3. SMD reserves our rights to disclose your personal information where you have given us explicit legal written consent to do so.
  4. SMD reserves the right to monitor user and network traffic for site security purposes and prevent any unauthorized attempts to tamper with our site or cause damage to our property.
  5. SMD reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy or update it. Where a major change is made, customers will be informed by e-mail notification or through a notice on our website. Customers and site visitors bear the responsibility to ensure that they have read the changes or updates as the case may be.
